<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chart on Ottmar’s Notes</title>
    <link>https://ogobrecht.github.io/tags/chart/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chart on Ottmar’s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ogobrecht.github.io/tags/chart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Major Version of D3 Force Network Chart Available</title>
      <link>https://ogobrecht.github.io/posts/2018-12-02-new-major-version-of-d3-force-network-chart-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ogobrecht.github.io/posts/2018-12-02-new-major-version-of-d3-force-network-chart-available/</guid>
      <description>Since APEX version 5 was published with the Universal Theme, I was thinking that I needed something for better responsiveness of the graph. Although it was possible to configure the graph to use the DOM parent width, the responsiveness was not so good because of situations where the window size does not change (we use the window resize event to trigger the change of the width) but the available space for the graph changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APEX Plugin dhtmlxGantt</title>
      <link>https://ogobrecht.github.io/posts/2017-03-14-apex-plugin-dhtmlx-gantt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ogobrecht.github.io/posts/2017-03-14-apex-plugin-dhtmlx-gantt/</guid>
      <description>Some weeks ago I was asked, if I can create a plugin for the Gantt chart library from dhtmlx.com. I had a look at the library and I thought that it should be possible.
Because all my plugin developments are free time projects it took a while. Now the first public version is available. It is based on the GPLv2 version of the library, which has a reduced set of functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting mal anders, Markdown sei Dank</title>
      <link>https://ogobrecht.github.io/posts/2016-11-17-reporting-mal-anders-markdown-sei-dank/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ogobrecht.github.io/posts/2016-11-17-reporting-mal-anders-markdown-sei-dank/</guid>
      <description>Die Folien zu meinem Vortrag:
Open HTML presentation in a new window/tab
You need a modern browser with activated JavaScript. Navigation tips:
 Space = Next slide Shift + Space = Previous slide Esc = Overview all slides ? = Overview all keyboard shortcuts All links are opened in a new window/tab   Kurzdarstellung:
Markdown hat sich in den letzten Jahren als vereinfachte Auszeichnungssprache zur HTML-Erstellung durchgesetzt. Es genügt ein einfacher Texteditor und wenige, allgemein gebräuchliche Konventionen, um z.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D3.js Force-Directed Network Chart</title>
      <link>https://ogobrecht.github.io/posts/2015-02-20-d3js-force-directed-network-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ogobrecht.github.io/posts/2015-02-20-d3js-force-directed-network-chart/</guid>
      <description>My first Oracle APEX plugin and open source project :-)
Everything started some months ago when I stumbled over this fascinating force-directed graph. I immediately had the idea to use this technology to visualize data models in APEX. My experience is, that direct after I documented a data model, this documentation is out of date. I wanted to have a live visualization of the data models. After the first implementation it turned out, that the resulting graph is also useful for other purposes and I decided to build up an APEX plugin for easier integration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>